Welcome back. This is the first video in our long series of the
欢迎回来。这是我们长长的系列视频中的第一个
implementation of compilers, The call from last time that a compiler has five phases.
编译器的实现，从上次调用到编译器有五个阶段。
We're gonna begin by talking about lexical analysis and this will probably take us
我们将从讨论词汇分析开始，这可能需要我们
three to four videos to get through at least and then we'll, we will be moving on
三到四个录像带至少要通过，然后我们会，我们会继续
in order to the other phases. Let's start by looking at a small code fragment. The
以便进入其他阶段。让我们从看一小段代码开始。这个
goal of lexical analysis is to divide this piece of code up. Into lexical units so
词法分析的目标是划分这段代码。转换成词汇单位，因此
things like the keyword if the variable names i, n, j and the relational operator
例如关键字，如果变量名为i，n，j和关系运算符
double-equals and so on. Now as a human being this is. As we discussed last time
两个相等，以此类推。现在，作为一个人类，这就是。正如我们上次讨论的那样
this is a very easy thing to do because there are all kinds of visual clues about
这是一件非常容易做的事情，因为有各种各样的视觉线索
where the units lie Where the boundaries between the different units lie but a
单元所在的位置是不同单元之间的边界所在的位置，但是
program like lexical analyzer. It doesn't have that kind of luxury. In fact what
词法分析器之类的程序。它没有那种奢华。实际上是什么
the, what the likes of analyzer will see is something that looks more like this. So
像分析器这样的人会看到更像这样的东西。所以
here I overwritten, the code out just as a string, with all the white space symbols
在这里，我用所有的空格符号覆盖了代码，它只是一个字符串
included and is from, from this representation, this is a linear string,
包括并且来自该表示，这是一个线性字符串，
you can think of this as bytes in the file that the lexical analyzer has to work and
您可以将其视为文件中的字节，词法分析器必须
it's going to mark through, placing dividers between the different units. So,
它将会打通，在不同的单元之间放置分隔符。所以,
it will recognize that there's a division there, between the white space and the
它将认识到在那里有一个分界线，在空白和
keyword. Then a division after the keyword and there's more a wide space, the open
关键字。然后在关键字后面进行划分，还有更大的空白处，即空白处
paren, the i, another wide space, double equals and so on and it goes through
帕伦，i，另一个宽空格，双等，以此类推，它通过
drawing these lines diving up. The, the string into its lexical unit, So I won't
画这些线往上潜。将字符串转换成它的词汇单元，所以我不会
finish the whole thing but you should get the idea. Now, it doesn't just place these
把整件事做完，但你应该明白其中的意思。现在，它不仅仅是把这些
dividers in the string however. It doesn't just recognize the substrings. It also
不过，字符串中的分隔符。它不仅识别子字符串。它还
needs to classify the different elements of the string according to their role. We
需要根据不同的角色对字符串的不同元素进行分类。我们
call these token classes. Or sometimes, I'll just call it the class of the token.
将这些令牌类称为令牌类。或者，有时我会简单地称它为令牌的类。
And in English, these roles are things like noun, verb, adjective. Okay and there
在英语中，这些角色是名词、动词、形容词。好的，还有这里
is, ther e are many more or at least or some more. And in the programming
就是，还有更多，或者至少更多。并且在编程中
language, the classes, the token classes would be things like identifiers,
语言、类、令牌类可能是标识符之类的东西，
Keywords. I, and then individual pieces of syntax like an open paren or a close
关键字。i，然后是各个语法片段，如开放的Paren或关闭的
paren, those are the classes by themselves. A, numbers. And again, there
帕伦，那些都是自己的课。A，数字。再一次，在那里
are more classes but there's a thick set of classes and each one of these
有更多的类，但是有一组密集的类，其中的每一个
corresponds to some set of strings that could appear in a program. So token
对应于可能出现在程序中的某组字符串。所以令牌
classes correspond to sets of strings, And [inaudible] strings can be described
类对应于字符串集，并且可以描述[听不见的]字符串
relatively straightforwardly so for example. The token class of identifiers in
例如，相对直截了当地说。中的标识符令牌类
most programming languages might be something like strings of letters or
大多数编程语言可能是类似于字符串或
digits, starting with a letter. So for example, a variable name or identifier
数字，以字母开头。例如，变量名或标识符
could be something like a1 or it could be f00 or it could be, b17, all of those
可能是A1，也可能是f00，也可能是B17，所有这些
would be, be valid identifiers and often, often they'll be additional characters
是有效的标识符，并且通常是附加字符
that allowed identifiers but that's the basic idea, Very, very often The main
这允许使用标识符，但这是基本思想，通常主要是
restriction identifiers that they have to start, with a letter, An integer and
它们必须以字母、整数和
typical definition of an integer is a non-empty string of digits. So, something
整数的典型定义是非空的数字字符串。所以，有些东西
like zero or twelve. Okay. One followed by two I should say is actually a string of
比如0或12。好吧。一后面跟着两个，我应该说实际上是一串
number in this case. And, and yeah, it is actually whether admit some numbers you
在这种情况下是号码。而且，是的，实际上是你是否接受了一些数字
might not think of. Things like 001 would be a valid representation of a number or
可能想不到。像001这样的东西将是数字或
even 00 could be a valid integer according to this definition. Keywords are typically
根据该定义，偶数00可以是有效的整数。关键字通常是
just a fix set of reserved words and so here I've listed a few, else, if, begin,
只有一组固定的保留字，所以我在这里列出了几个，其他的，如果，BEGIN，
and so on. And then white space as itself a token class so we actually have to say
诸若此类。然后空格本身就是一个令牌类，所以我们实际上不得不说
in that string which is the representation of the program what every character in
在表示程序字符串中，每个字符
that string, what token or what token class it's a part of. What every substring
该字符串、哪个令牌或它是哪个令牌类的一部分。每个子字符串
is a part of and that includes the white space. So, for example if we have a series
是的一部分，包括空白。例如，如果我们有一系列
of three blanks, if I say if and then an open paren and I have three blanks in
三个空格中，如果我说如果，然后一个空格，帕伦和我有三个空格
here, these three blank s would be grouped together as white space. So the goal of
在这里，这三个空格将组合在一起作为空格。所以我们的目标是
lexical analysis is to classify substrings of the program according to their role.
词法分析是根据程序的子字符串的角色对其进行分类。
This is the, the token class, okay? Is it a keyword, a variable identifier, And then
这是令牌课，好吗？它是关键字、变量标识符，然后
to communicate these tokens, to the parser. So, drawing a picture here, let's
将这些令牌传递给解析器。那么，在这里画一幅画，让我们
switch colors. The lexical analyzer communicates with the parser. Okay and the
切换颜色。词法分析器与解析器通信。好的，还有
functionality here is that, the lexical analyzer takes in a string. Typically
这里的功能是，词法分析器接受一个字符串。通常
stored up, also just a sequence of bytes and then when [inaudible] to the parser is
存储起来，也只是一个字节序列，然后当解析器[听不到]时
sequence or pairs which are the token class. And substring which I would say
作为令牌类的序列或对。以及我想说的子字符串
string here, that, that, of which is the sets of string which is a part of the
字符串在这里，那个，那个，其中是字符串的集合，它是
input along with the class the role that it plays in the in the language, and this
与班级一起输入它在语言中扮演的角色，这
pair together is called a token. So for example, if my string is that f00 = 42,
组合在一起称为令牌。例如，如果我字符串是f00=42，
all right, then that will go to the lexical analyzer and that will come, I'll
好的，然后这些会被送到词汇分析器那里，那会来的，我会
write down here, three tokens. And these would be identifier. Who? Operator say
在这里写下，三个代币。这些将是标识符。谁?操作员说
equals. And. Integer, excuse me 42. And here I just left these things as strings
相等。和。整数，打扰一下42。在这里，我只是把这些东西留作字符串
to, to emphasize that these are strings. So this is not the number 42 at this point
为了强调这些都是字符串。所以在这一点上这不是42号
in time, it's, it's the string 42 which is a plays an integer role in the programming
在时间上，它是字符串42，它在编程中扮演一个整数角色
language. And then these, and when the price that takes this input is this
语言。然后是这些，当接受这一投入的价格是这样的
sequence of pairs. So the lexical analyzer essentially runs over the input string and
配对序列。因此，词法分析器基本上会遍历输入字符串，并且
chunks it up into the sequence of pairs where each pair is a token class and a
将其分块成对序列，其中每对都是一个令牌类和一个
substring of the original input. As we turn to the example from the beginning of
原始输入的子字符串。当我们从一开始就看这个例子时，
the video, here it is written out as a string. And our goal now is to lexically
视频，这里是以字符串的形式写出来的。我们现在的目标是在词汇上
analyze this fragment of code. We want to go through and identify the substrings
分析这段代码。我们要检查并标识子字符串
that are tokens and also their token classes. So, to do this, we're gonna need
它们是令牌，也是它们的令牌类。所以，要做到这一点，我们需要
some token classes. So let's give ourselves some of those to work with.
一些令牌类。因此，让我们给自己一些这样的东西来工作吧。
We'll need white space. And, and so this is sequences of blanks, new lines tab,
我们需要空格。这是一系列的空格，换行符，
things like that with the keywords. And we'll need variables which we'll call
关键字之类的东西。我们需要我们称之为变量的变量
identifiers. And we'll need integers and now I'll call those numbers. Here and then
标识符。我们需要整数，现在我给这些数字取名。此时此刻
we're going to have some other operations some other classes things like open paren
我们会有一些其他的操作，一些其他的类，比如Open Paren
close paren, and semi colon and these are interesting. These three ae interesting
关闭Paren和分号，这些都很有趣。这三个很有趣
because they're single character token classes that is, is a set of strings but
因为它们是单字符令牌类，也就是说，是一组字符串，但是
is only, is only one string in the set so the open paren corresponds to exact
是唯一的，则集合中只有一个字符串，因此打开的Paren对应于Exact
[inaudible] strings that contain only open paren. So often the punctuation marks of
[听不见]仅包含打开的Paren的字符串。通常情况下，标点符号
the language are in token classes all by themselves. Another piece of punctuation
这些语言都是单独出现在符号类中的。另一条标点符号
that we'll add here is, is assignments. That will be a token class by itself
我们在这里要添加的是任务。这本身将是一个令牌类
because it's such an important operation. But, the double equals will class as a
因为这是一个非常重要的手术。但是，双等分将被归类为
relational operator with this class as an operator put it up here. Alright, So now
将这个类作为运算符的关系运算符放在这里。好的，那么现在
what we're going to do is we're gonna go through and tokenized this string and I'm
我们要做的是，我们要检查并标记化这个字符串，我
going to write down for each substring. What class it is. You know, I'm just gonna
我要写下每个子字符串。这是什么班？你知道吗，我正要
use the first letter here of the class. It's indicated just to save time so I
在这里用班级的第一个字母。指示只是为了节省时间，所以我
don't have to write everything up. Hence, we change colors so we can do this in a
没必要把每件事都写下来。因此，我们更改颜色，以便可以在
different color. So, the first token here is white space token and then that
不同的颜色。所以，这里的第一个令牌是空格令牌，然后是
followed by the F keyword. So, okay, And then we have a blank here which is another
后跟关键字F。所以，好的，然后我们这里有一块空白，这是另一块
white space and then the open paren which is its own token class so I'll just leave
空格，然后是开放的Paren，这是它自己的令牌类，所以我就离开
it to identify itself there and then we have an identifier. Okay, White space and
它在那里标识自己，然后我们就有了一个标识符。好的，空格和
then an operator, the double-equals. Another blank so that's white space
然后是一个运算符，即双等式。另一个空格，所以那是空格
followed by another identifier followed by close parens, Again, a punctuation mark in
后面紧跟另一个标识符，后跟右括号，同样是中的标点符号
a token class by itself. And then we have three white space characters so those are
令牌类本身。然后我们有三个空格字符，所以它们是
group together as a white space token, Followed by another identifier and more
作为空格标记组合在一起，后跟另一个标识符等
white space and then another single character token, the assignment operator,
空格，然后是另一个单字符标记、赋值运算符
white space and a number, And then sem i colon again and punctuation mark and a
空格和数字，然后是sem i冒号，再加上标点符号和a
token class by itself. Two white space characters can group together. What
令牌类本身。两个空格字符可以组合在一起。什么
follows in is a keyword, so it gets classified as in the keyword token class.
后面是一个关键字，因此它被归类为Keyword Token类中的关键字。
Another run of white space characters and then another identifier. There's actually
又一串空格字符，然后是另一个标识符。实际上有一个
a blank there where we almost covered it up without marks. The assignment operator
一片空白，我们几乎没留下任何痕迹就把它遮住了。赋值运算符
by itself in a token class, white space, a number, and finally the semi colon by
在标记类中本身、空格、数字，最后是分号by
itself. And there is our tokenization. We've identified the substrings and we've
它本身。这就是我们的象征化。我们已经确定了子串，我们已经
also labeled each one with its token class.
还用它的令牌类给每一个都贴上了标签。